okay good evening ladies and gentlemen
at this time we are returning to open
session after having boarded previously
to go into executive session to discuss
the strategy with respect to potential
litigation entertain discussion with
respect to the issue of 100 Peel Street
in Hingham
we have with us tonight our state
counsel for the town attorney Susan
Murphy please join us at the table and
just briefly give us a backdrop of the
issue before us tonight
in 2001 the Board of Selectmen and the
then word of the Housing Authority
entered into a Memorandum of
Understanding which was very brief it's
a one-page agreement pursuant to which
the town agreed to pay for the costs of
demolition and cleanup of two old
structures on 15 approximately 15 acres
of land owned by the Housing Authority
on Beale Street these structures were
building similar to the ones that bear
Cove park in that area that had become
dilapidated and had some hazardous
materials in them such as asbestos of
those types of materials that then town
administrator I understand spoke to the
Housing Authority board about the fact
that the town was remediating these
buildings on Town land but that you know
town could not pay to do it on land it
did not own which was a Housing
Authority land and a agreement was
struck where in consideration for the
town paying the cost of demolition and
remediation that the housing authority
would transfer eight of the
fifteen acre parcel that it owned on
Beale Street the matter went before town
meeting to authorize the town to acquire
the land town meeting approved it
letters went from the housing authority
to the federal government who at that
time but no longer does held
restrictions related to the land stating
that they no longer had any need for the
land etc the town did the work the town
Accounts Office has located a
documentation that the town paid to do
the work for reasons which are not fully
known there was a gap in time between
that work happening and before there
being a realization that no deed had
ever been recorded and this was
discovered about a year and a half or so
ago - two years brought to the Housing
Authority's attention through multiple
meetings both of the former Town
Administrator ted alexei otis and i'm
karin johnson as liaison to the housing
authority and there's been multiple
meetings over the last year and a half
at least three to four and at the most
recent meeting that I attended with
Lichtman Johnson and Michelle Montsegur
a vote was taken as to whether or not
the the Housing Authority would follow
through on its commitment to execute a
deed and take whatever other steps are
necessary to convey the eight acres to
the town and the Housing Authority voted
three votes against and only two votes
in favor and therefore the motion failed
so at this point in time there's an
agreement with a commitment the town has
been taxpayer dollars on the demolition
of this project and has not received any
consideration in return for spending
taxpayer dollars on land that the town
does not own and that is the current
state of affairs I don't know
fleckner Johnson have anything no I
appreciate that summary as you can tell
from Susan's description this has been a
long process both in terms of you know
the the contract and the removal of the
building and then the discovery of the
the lack of the deed and conversations
with the housing authority that I I at
least joined in 2017 we have had ongoing
discussions with the housing authorities
since 2017 they've asked some good
questions we've provided them with all
of the diligence materials that they've
requested over time so that they you
know could fully understand their
obligation under the signed contract
from 2001 and there's been no
disagreement that the contract exists
there's been no disagreement that the
buildings were removed so that the town
had had provided full consideration
under the 2001 contract there's no
disagreement on any of that and so we've
reached an impasse where the last
several meetings were and we've gone
before them to discuss okay well what
else do you need to understand your
obligation here and to fulfill your
obligation under the contract
we really haven't there is nothing else
they say this is it
so we have a signed agreement you know
at the time you know folks in the
audience may remember there is a series
of derelict buildings in in and around
that bear Cove Park area that were a
public nuisance and actually dangerous
and you know one of the things I thought
about was so you know here's the town
the town is aware withal to take these
buildings down
we were actually contacted by our
insurance agent to do just that
and we get to the we get to the line
right we get to the fence with our
neighbor the housing authority and we
have the ability to take these buildings
down and they don't because they don't
have any cash and we say all right we're
gonna take we're gonna take down what we
view as derelict and and dangerous
building but but we're not gonna look
across the fence to our neighbor the
housing authority and say hey we'll help
you out too that's what the town did in
2001 and what we're asking for is the
Housing Authority to live up to its the
promise that it made to pay the town
to pay the taxpayers of the town for the
work that the town did it's a you know
it's a it's a pretty straightforward
contract question and I we we've come to
an impasse in the conversations with the
housing authority and that's why as a
liaison to the housing authority I
requested this executive session tonight
so that I could fully brief you on the
potential for litigation which I
unfortunately view as as the place where
at any of the housing authority members
sign the contract with the town in 2001
still on the housing authority yes -
Robert Keys and James Watson were
members in 2001 their signatures appear
on contract and they are still members
of the housing authority and with a part
of the majority to voted against
transferring this yes they were they
were two of the three that voted against
the transfer public discussion hearing
none I'll entertain a motion to file
litigation regarding the enforcement of
agreement as to one hundred bills three
didn't hang a mess second favor all
right okay entertain a motion to approve
the minutes date of February 12th 2019
so moved second well as a favor
I might warn article article H transfer
for a meal stabilized a new staff
Stabilization Fund
just ketchup I do you don't mind okay so
the meals tax table this is an annual
article historically this money has been
used for to reduce the tax rate with
relation is related to the debt service
on the middle school I believe and we're
we're outside of that schedule now
there's about a hundred and twenty seven
thousand dollars remaining in this
account and the intent and this fund and
the intent is to either use it to empty
the account the fund to continue to pay
down a capital project for instance or
to leave it there so if you want a
recommendation from me I would suggest
that we use it to pay down a large
capital project for instance the
dredging project for instance that we're
going to have to go out to issue a debt
so the dredging that we heard about
previously that we would borrow right to
fund this would just defray some leave
defray about a hundred and twenty
thousand dollars of that that's right
okay and does the fun do we have to take
a vote to close this fund out or does
the fund what was it zero about the fun
yes so what I suggest we do is that we
we fund the that item with that quite
frankly it's really probably going to be
ad cons call how that works I would
suggest you simply take favorable action
on it tonight and we'll make it all make
a recommendation on your behalf to
advisory about what that comment and
what their motion might look like but
the is you know
okay and so at addcom would know the
balance of the Stabilization Fund yeah
we were to make we'd make a
recommendation but it might be up to ad
con con to direct where the balance of
the Stabilization Fund goes so what will
fund the bet will fund the the amount of
the balance at the time of the
transaction I say so because it's it's
constantly earning earning interest so
we don't want to pick a number now
because it would be insufficient we'd
end up with 17 cents in an account okay
that we wouldn't be able to close out so
okay and just the don't recommend the
background on this was that initially
when the meals tax when when Town
Meeting voted to authorize the meals tax
we put all the money in a stabilization
account and then we we basically drew
that down when when the middle school
opened there was about two million
dollars in the Stabilization Fund and so
we took about half a million dollars
each year to defray the taxpayer impact
that was the tax relief that we
experienced with the middle school a few
years ago when when the meals tax when
Town Meeting authorized the town to move
the meals tax revenue into local
receipts we've basically been drawing
down this Stabilization Fund and this is
the little bit that's left it's it's
like in a sense we kind of had one bank
account and we switched banks and you
know we wrote all our checks and we've
got a little bit of money left from my
perspective what I said to Tom earlier
today is when Town Meeting adopted the
meals tax it was under the premise that
it be used not for everyday expenses not
for operating expenses but to defray the
costs of capital projects so for me the
principle that's important here is this
very small residual balance be applied
to a capital project because that's how
that that to me was an important card
that was an important part of town
meetings discussion I'd like to do it on
a project that's that Town Meeting is
considering this year so that we can
close it out and I think we have a
couple options but again I'd that that
principle of applying it to a capital
project would would be the only
condition that that I'd ask to be placed
on it
discussion hearing none entertainment
you've got a hand Andy Michael a knee
with the Advisory Committee so the
article age talked about a transfer to
defray the 2020 fiscal year tax rate so
it's fair to say that the board is
determined that's more of an economic
benefit for the taxpayer to use this
small hundred twenty thousand to defray
the borrowing costs then to make in
significant impact on the tax rate as
head I think we're still carrying the
$500,000 under I'd though right yes we
are so where where this is just the fact
that we this is just the fact that we
had this the old Stabilization Fund so
we used to segregate meals tax we don't
segregate meals tax anymore so right so
I suppose you could just add this on to
the $500,000 under I'd that we carry
that we fund with the meals tax right or
you or you could do this andis bringing
up a good question and without getting
into the weeds on this on you know you
want to well financially weeds yes so
the the article is written is for
purposes of reducing the tax rate which
begs the question to me and thank you
for asking the question of whether this
has to be actually applied to an
excluded debt project because if you
think about the dredging project or the
the the windows at the high school or
something those are being funded with
non excluded debts so they would not
achieve the purpose of reducing the tax
rate so what if we want to follow the
letter of article H that would suggest
to me that that an alternate use besides
what we've just spoken about is to just
make an extra hundred and what seventy
whatever a thousand dollar payment
against the middle school which in
effect reduces the tax rate for next
year because it's excluded debt I can
work
and II on some of the options that they
might consider with regards to their
motion it could be also fungible right
you know we could whatever it gets too
complicated I guess you could use some
of the underride money to fund this
keeping the underride constant at a half
a million dollars we could split it
among all the different so I think what
we're hearing here is is that the board
has consensus that we'd like to close
this out because we've we've been now
it's it's a little bit of money that's
hanging out there that we would like to
apply it to a capital project which is
keeping within the spirit of it and
maybe there's just a follow-up on the
mechanics to ensure that the project
it's applied to is in compliance with
the wording of the article so long as
Andy's not bitter that we're kicking it
to him - we had some fun at the planning
board meeting last night make a motion
to recommend favorable action on article
h ii Laurens lane so any did it um if
you would open the public hearing this
is a public hearing so if you could I do
that to the chairman public hearing as
it relates to Martins Lane discussion
when you're discussing previously okay
so this is the public hearing on the
intention and the Board of Selectmen to
lay out forty square feet as part of
Martins Lane the board had previously
had this on your agenda a little less
than a month ago at that time you
referred the matter to the Planning
Board pursuant to statutory process the
Planning Board took it up at a public
meeting at which point they voted to
recommend acceptance notice of this
public hearing was sent to
the owner of record and also because the
owner of record we believe is not an
entity that currently exists in
Massachusetts any longer
it was also posted in Town Hall in order
to cover all posting requirements and it
any copy was made available at the town
clerk's office so at this point in time
you know and unless there's any anyone
who wishes to be heard on it if the
Board of Selectmen wishes Town Meeting
to take up the warrant article to accept
this forty square foot area they told me
it would require the Board of Selectmen
to take the vote which I believe has
been provided to you Town Meeting cannot
act on a street acceptance unless the
selectmen have voted to lay it out we
discussed this previously but to the
extent that has any further questions
I'll entertain them now public all right
all in that case ruled that we won't
favorable acts there's a vote you have
to take notice some attention that we
move to both favorably on notice of the
intention to lay out as part of the
public way known as Martins Lane and
approximately forty square foot parcel
the land located to the west of the
North westerly terminus of the existing
layout of Martins Lane as shown on a
plan entitled quote layout plan Martins
Lane Hingham aspen of county and quote
dated February for 2019 prepared by
Beals and Thomas Inc having been sent by
first-class mail to the owner of record
and post it in a public place on less
than seven days prior to the date of
this public meeting in accordance with
Mass General or chapter 82 second 22 the
Board of Selectmen hereby or
layout of set forty square feet of
square foot parcel as big part of
Martin's claim second all's favor we've
got two seats did you greetings
greetings jack - president Hingham high
school rowing association with me here
is looking greenly our program director
and of course dot Jim Quattro mone from
if I this evening we're presenting a
continuation of a pilot program for the
spring training on the back river based
at bear Cove park began this pilot
program in the spring of 2018 the
program did very well there so this year
time spent training on the water early
season was significantly greater than it
was in the previous season therefore
we're proposing to essentially do the
same program again this season okay my
colleagues have any questions when are
you gonna start March 18 okay and I know
that when you're getting the boats in
the water and things the the student
athletes are kind of in the water a
little bit more than if they were in a
dock I'm just wondering about you know
temperature the water and it's gonna be
mighty cold in March it is exceptionally
cold - the water stays cold longer so
last year we found a good system
combination of waterproof socks gore-tex
socks and easily like Crocs or something
on their feet that would get them they
cannot they only need to go down to
about there
level so we found out a system that
worked well last year for them and that
will do the same this year we'll just
put out to all the parents and with the
specs this is what we recommend for the
clothing and they should do very well
with that is that so it turned out well
after a few couple couple days of
figuring it out and that's well do the
same there and Tom this this mou runs
for is it just the spring season or is
it also for the fall only the spring
it's only the spring end we need ok the
fall will be a deck at agency okay same
as last season right okay
um and though you'll have the temporary
storage will use the fence have the
porta-potties and the boats wall behind
a locked fence okay and I see the
Harbormaster here I think the program
from your perspective worked well is
what I understood okay no I mean I I'm
I'm all for getting them out on the
water as soon as we can so pretty well
last year so take a motion first one is
and just with respect to the agreement
that's in front you there's going to be
just an update for some of the notice
contacts for the for that high school
rowing program so that will be one minor
change or just updating names in the
notice provision so that will be
something that will just get that paper
up it's on page six they have some
individuals named and they're just gonna
update that the other thing that I just
want to mention if I could just what we
have everybody in the room together
which is um this is the second year of
what's being termed a pilot program I
believe I mentioned it when we gathered
last year for the same conversation that
this required National Park Service
approval which we got very quickly last
year and again this year
but it can't be forever a pilot program
and there are some formalities in order
to make it more permanent I have heard
that you know both the rowing program so
the bear cub Park Committee and have
talked favorably about making it a more
permanent program but that means we need
to get started probably much earlier I
would recommend that by the end of the
summer if there's discussion about
trying to put it in we'd have to change
some paper we have to do some paperwork
with the National Park Service and also
I know that lonnie Fournier at the
conservation office would like to just
talk about how you know things get
managed if it's a long-term project so I
would just encourage to the extent
people are interested and kind of
keeping this going that you know we just
get started earlier next year or early
like in the fall of this year to start
putting all those pieces in place I mean
I think we want to be supportive of this
effort I think it's it's been working
well for everybody and so you know we
don't want the National Park Service a
year from now to you know we don't want
any hiccups so you know I'd also say
that that you know sometimes when we
kind of wait till the fall you get you
get well into your fall season and
you've got new students and all that you
know let's even get on it in the summer
if we need to just so that we don't find
ourselves running out of time and and
limiting what's really a great
partnership and I would note you know it
seems that the vehicle park committees
in support of this as well right no
objection
I move that the Board of Selectmen of
acting is the board of park
commissioners approved and enter into a
memorandum of understanding with Hingham
public schools to allow the use of bear
Cove Park to access the back river for
the Hingham high school rowing program
for the spring 2019 season subject to
delivery to the Board of Selectmen of
updated certificates of insurance prior
to the commencement of use including
staging within the park that's where our
our sailing program and it would run our
sailing program last year identify your
team yes so Joe Griffin our head sailing
coach go see ya our sailing program last
year had these racks in place to be able
to launch from the bathing beach before
the docks for noon at HMC we were we
would respectfully ask that we'd be able
to do that again this year any questions
from my colleagues no again I just
mention again that I think this is
another example of the great cooperation
due to the hard work of a lot of people
in this room to you know kind of help
each other out so this is getting this
is getting the sailing team up and
running and also we know that for for
hang a Maritime Center that that the
earlier in the season those docks get in
the more wear and tear that can be
pretty punishing in the harbor in March
and April so I think we've we've been
trying to work together on creative
solutions that meet everybody's needs
and it's it's nice to see us being able
to build off a success from last year we
certainly appreciate that
the audience no okay take emotions I'll
make a motion that the Board of
Selectmen asked acting as the board of
park commissioners approved the
temporary location of storage racks for
the Hingham high school sailing team at
Hingham harbor for the period ending on
April 30th 2019 in the locations shown
on the aerial plan submitted to the town
administrator on January 11th 2019
second thanks so much thank you thanks
for coming tonight
mr. Olsen good evening good evening
Sylvester DiNapoli we have here we ever
put a wall to the table we have a
proposed Waterman extension along
Abington Street initiating from the
entrance to the social educational
collaborative which is parking at the
Weymouth town line on abacus Street
extending an 8 inch main approximately
1350 feet to the entrance of proposed
daycare facility little sprouts located
at approximately 73 Abington Street the
water may extension the proposed water
extension also includes a fire hydrant
at the end of that want to make
extension so the primary purpose is to
deliver water to the daycare facility as
I mentioned but also for the proposed if
approved other facilities not sure what
the status of that development is are a
storage facility so would be leaving
stubs to provide service for that in the
future if it's approved and we
understand that the the street is a
guaranteed Street this is the last year
of 2019 as the last year on the five
year moratorium but due to the service
needs of this facility we're looking for
the town to waive that for this portion
and I I guess Harry can speak for the
engineering department on on that
so the driveway
school yes that's the existing
termination no terminus of the existing
water system there's a fire hydrant
right there in a valve and a stub that
was put there for future extension and
the plan is to extend from there it
looks like there's some kind of
configuration with a is this property
presently constructed or contemplated
before you get to the proposed daycare
facility that's the proposed or
contemplated facilities
I believe it's proposed to be a storage
facility but the three buildings yes yes
I'm not sure what phase of the planning
and approval process that DC properties
and is is somebody here for the
applicant mr. Sullivan perhaps you could
take the podium and just give us a brief
thumbnail this discussion as to what
what's going on here and where you fit
into this project this has been quite a
journey for water so I'm the attorney
representing the applicant for the
school that's been completed the board
may remember I was here in November I'm
seeking a road cutting permit so that we
could get water for the school the
school has been completed and has been
vacant not with staying the fact that
there are students and families that
wish to use it we don't have a
certificate of occupancy because we
don't have access to water recognizing
there was a moratorium we reached out to
Anna butter to get an easement from them
when the board turned us down for
cutting into the road as mr. Olson
suggested we then pursued the easement
from air gas which is right behind us
which would not require us to cut into
the road
I believe the DPW has now come forward
in
suggested that we cut into Abington
Street and go up that way we're sort of
held hostage we need to open we have
families that have signed up we have
people that want to work the school so
we're here at the request of the
selectmen hoping that somehow we can get
some water and get moving
so I remember you came in in in November
because it was the most unusual it was
an unusual thing and I just want to read
this because this is dated Tuesday
November 6 2018 dear Tom Tom Mayo I am
following up on my letter late last
month regarding getting before the
selectmen essentially Aquarion is
requiring that we get a letter from the
selectmen that permission to cut into
Abington Street to tie into the water
main will not be granted since the
moratorium is in place our client has
arranged for an easement that will
result in no disturbance to the public
way but Aquarion requires that in order
to use an easement for water service
that the selectmen must refuse to allow
the applicant to cut into a public way
still on a moratorium so you came in in
November and asked for that no vote
which we gave correct and I kind of
thought that would be the end of it I
was I was a little surprised that this
was back up on the agenda and so I'm
kind of wondering what what happened it
seemed like there was an agreement in
place with all the parties that that
this easement would would be done so
what excuse me what nice I can't really
address that I do know that yeah for
some reason or another I don't know what
fell through the cracks but the request
to cut into the Avenue Street never came
to our office so we were unaware that
there was a request to put that water
main in Avenue Street we felt you feel
now as we give den we strongly recommend
the board selecting to approve the water
main be installed in the road as of
right now I think it's a one and a half
inch with too much water meant water
from service so it's considered a main
and having a street served by Abington
Rockland water the reason why that main
was put in in the early 60s because all
those homes were on wells
they went dry the DPW superintendent the
time had some extra electrical conduit
from what I understand hmm neither
dealing with Abington Rockland supply
those houses with water if they put that
electrical conduit in the ground right
now there's no ownership of that water
made in the ground every time there's a
water break which is numerous they cut
the road and the resident in the rate
payers are having street pay for that
repair there's no fire service up there
at all for hydrants on the entire length
of Abington Street so we recommend we
get this 1,800 feet or whether it may be
started in the ground on Abington Street
so there's a form of water made to
connect I have been involved in several
times with trying to get a formal 8 inch
water service was made up there over the
last 20 years but the expense of
bringing water end to that location was
just too much for any of the private
entities to pay for to install that
water so now we have water that was
brought to the end of Avenue Street from
Weymouth line might not develop up five
years ago I think it was and now we have
an opportunity to extend it put a formal
water main and at least a third of that
road you have fire protection and a
third of the road we possibly in the
future it's done it down the entire
winding and so Harry who will who will
be responsible for the cost of the
installation of this water main the
developer will be paying with the water
main in and also make the road repairs
to put the world back in is uh probably
as close to the conditioner said now if
not better
I guess what's what's a little unusual
is that you - typically it's a little
unusual for the engineering department
to be recommending that the board cut
into a street before the moratorium has
has correct that's done and let me just
ask because I'm not as good at reading
the plans as Paul is but is is this
solution which I understand the
developer is going to pay how does the
cost of this solution
compared to the solution of the easement
that was initially contemplated is this
is this a big burden on well if I can I
back up for a second when I came to and
I wrote that email to Tom Mayo we had
spent months negotiating with not only
aquarium but two different abutters to
try to get water because we recognized
this was a problem so we did think that
was just the hurdle and this was pro
forma to come before the selectmen which
is why we wrote that letter I think
there's been a change from from where
the DPW stands now an aquarium so yes it
will be more expensive to us to bring
the water down avek to the street than
to go through the easement but you know
we just need water mm-hmm
I mean that's sort of where we stand and
and we've sort of been caught in the
middle by all this no and I understand
and actually a Egham resident who is a
new parent actually phoned our office
and you know I I think it's it's an
unfortunate situation that we have you
know I spoke to a resident in a ham
taxpayer who has an eight week old child
and is making the transition back to the
work force and you know that's that's
that's a difficult time as it is and I
think the the anxiety that this is
creating not just on that family but
potentially on others is is is not lost
on on the board again it it it sort of
caught us by surprise based on the last
time we we talked about this so I think
we get we get the urgency here what is
the proposed use
constructing here so okay so for the
three buildings there's three different
uses miss really one is in like an easy
storage facility which is the bigger
building that you look at the other is
an elevator company that's potentially
going in there and the other is a
smaller you industrial building so those
are three different uses and we're just
about through the permitting process
with planning and zoning board in fact
we were before my associates before the
Zoning Board right now on this okay and
you've got that they've all the hearings
have been closed decisions have not been
issued
okay but the daycare facility itself has
been constructed it has it for quite a
while we had hope to open by January
okay and there are there are people who
I've understood and have had to try to
make alternate arrangements and it's
it's a dicey situation I think
lieutenants and applicants be too we
have a completed building has no access
to water mr. Olsen is there an intention
to look the water main there is a
proposed intention to loop the water in
yes it's always better to loop Amane and
have a dead end mmm-hmm we've been
trying to loop mains since I got here
three years ago I think we've looped
probably eight mains in the past three
years so does that enhance the water
pressure it's better for capacity and
water quality and reservist reliability
I love Russia not so much pressure flow
and capacity and service reliability are
we on the extreme end of the system and
we are it's the it's the end of the line
yeah it is is the main that's proposed
to be installed in Abington Street
contemplating the capacity to extend it
to the end of the street yes
it's a Tantra say it is and and if I may
if it would be quicker we would be
willing to do the easement in the first
instance and then connect once the
moratoriums up up in a year whatever the
board chooses but again we're sort of
desperate for water questions from the
audience okay this is how we do it ma'am
you go up to the podium you identify
yourself by name and address make
whatever statement you care to I
my name is Wendy Spano go this is my
first time doing this
I live on Abington Street I live in 31
AB industry with my mom and my sister
and we're concerned about this water
mean that's coming down our street once
proposed or Street because we do have
Abington and Rockland now is that going
to destroy upset the applecart here for
the rest of the residents on our street
that have that like do we have to pay
like when you do do this do we pay for
the aquarium water company that money
you know the the water department you
know the water bills for that and then
when it when everything and proposing
and boosting it up to our street is you
know is that gonna like because like we
said we have part of the water we're
part of the on that water pipe line too
so I just want to know this is just I
don't know why sports we've got there
because if there's no water source why
would you build right there you know I
don't I don't understand because this is
a residential street and has been there
for so long you know why I have an
answer for that but I prefer to defer to
the parties that are present that
specialize in this particular area
perhaps I can adjust a couple things so
you primarily ask two questions one is
there any future plans to extend and
there aren't any there's no formal plans
to extend there is a desire to increase
the fire flow capacity in the area but
there's no current plans to extend and
your second question was being required
to connect or something not really Alec
to do that I was just wondering you know
with this whole those social collabo is
being built on the end of our street in
the whole water situation too we started
we had we went to a meeting with the
water company before some of the
residents we went there talked about
never wanted to do that before when they
were redoing our street before they
repaved knit they want to put a water
main down there and when they kind of
didn't do that so I didn't know what was
going on I think that was a 2014 votes
and I believe there was another
developer across the street for us from
73 having Street I forget the name of
officer that was going to build and I
think maybe they did build and that
proposed water my extension was for them
I think they determined that they didn't
need it they went there with their own
well so the existing water main
terminated that where it is right now at
the entrance to the South Shore
collaborative schools okay so can I ask
you you pay you pay right now Abington
Rockland water yes my mom does yes and
so her water service is not going to be
disturbed by this project
but in future like I we got a letter in
our milk in the mailbox saying that we
want to do future eventually what you
were just saying that you wanted to end
it all the way up to the Rockland side
with sharp Street is that will affect us
also so as part of the engineering
departments response to our grant
allocation application they made a
recommendation to the board and I'll
read it
we also recommend the board selectmen as
part of this grant of work be advertised
to all residents that reside on Avington
Street to have the chance to extend the
water main so it's just the chance
further into it to connect as part of
the water may extension so the water
line that exists currently to serve this
area is inadequate and does not provide
fire services as well as sufficient flow
which is what lieutenant Annapolis said
so our letter we read this and we took
it to heart and we basically sent a
letter to all the residents beyond 73 a
virgin street to shop street to say hey
we're hearing we're going to be here
tonight to talk about this and if
there's an opportunity or interest to
extend it further let us know so I've
heard from
residents that lived in that area too
were interested but not if they had to
pay for it which i think is what I would
you know if the question was pointed to
me that's why I would probably say two
and a third was interested he's at the
end of Abington Street he was five
African Street
his name is mr. schirra Tony Teixeira he
was interested he has a failing well so
he asked if he could connect to the
Edmonton Rockland line he said he didn't
think so so he was still interested in
in trying to connect so that's we did
our due diligence to see if there's any
interest which would be a supplemental
type of thing not part of this what's in
front of you and Steve how many
resonance are there about 25 residents
approximately maybe 23 a couple
businesses and the extension beyond 73
Abington Street would be the
responsibility of those residents along
that extension yes lieutenant in the
opinion of the fire department
I would this enhance the department's
ability to fight a fire up on that neck
of the woods absolutely I mean on
Christmas morning we had a fire at 43
Abington Street and that's pretty much
just about the middle of the street it
was about I believe 1,600 feet to one
hydrant and 1,800 feet to the other I
may end up having a call in a mutual aid
engine just to get enough hose and pump
up the street to the fire so anymore
Haydn's we can get I mean especially in
that area where we're so remote it's an
extended response time up there anyway
so any help we can get there is a fire
hydrant at the end of the line for fire
protection and or flushing right before
plus there's also a fire hydrant also at
the end of spring wood - I've seen it so
there's one right there and hurry in
that Street I'm sorry I'm sorry go ahead
and when they built that sweet spring
would they have a hydrant right at that
end of that street right there thank you
so did you get your questions answered
pretty much yeah okay thank you anybody
else even address if you would
hi my name's Marissa - Zadora 11 Pine
Grove Road Miriam where we spoke nice to
meet you nice to meet you too
so I am a potential patron of little
sprouts I have now ten-week-old
graduations thank you and I'm looking to
return to work I was supposed to return
April 1st so right now I'm I've been
searching day in and day out for any
nearby alternatives to cover you know
what was to be my return to work you
know just impacted by this hullabaloo
and I just like to know you know based
on what was said tonight there are three
other buildings in the area I that are
going up in that area I'd like to know
if if approved to extend the water main
is there priority given to just get the
service turned on at little sprouts or
is there other would there be
interruption due to extending it to the
other facilities as well I believe the
priorities those boughs okay and how
quickly do you think would you turn to
this mmm I think we probably start get
them in the ground
week after next if the contract is very
upset installing fight
I wouldn't think more than two weeks to
get that pipe install up to the driveway
into the building and that's what the
contractor did I think and that works
with your schedule I think also because
the proposed route goes past the wetland
there might be some conservation
involvement so we have to talk with
melania to make sure if if there's
something formal would have to be done
or it can be informal so I'm not sure
but that would be the only opening the
road of season in conservation other
than that it's contractors could put in
you know 100 250 feet a day so couple
weeks and how are you you have the
authority or ton engineering has the
authority to allow them to open the road
off cycle that's correct as long as the
weather is going to cooperate those no
problems with that starting early okay
and Harry in terms of the kind of the
you know the the repair to the road and
the restoration are you satisfied that
the conditions that are laid out in in
this letter that's in our packet are are
appropriate given where this road is and
I know sometimes when we've cut into
roads under the moratorium the
engineering department has you know
asked for example to go curb to curb or
to you know a to do some restoration a
little bit beyond what what is sometimes
typical Epping streets are rather unique
it was following our Platt those
potholes every one of the reason why we
get never fully reconstructed it is
because no water main in it it's a two
inch water service basically so we
crossed our fingers held on knows we
were in a paver over twice then we put
the micro seal on it
I've had five other towns come on so
what did you do with that road it come
on perfect I said well I can't take
really liked I designed what we did but
I can't wait to take craft look
initially came out in will be doing the
same process once the water mains in
over the open French we love one didn't
put the micro seals on it and won't come
off just as well thank you
I mean I have to say I'm just puzzled by
the lack of process here you know we
took that weird boat in the fall I don't
know it just doesn't seem like it should
have taken this long to get to this
place
well finish like I just want when they
came in November
this real print deadlines were closed on
the 15th we could extend them and at
that point in time as well but so really
I mean if we help to the deadlines and
this in the starting dates they were
still going to be in the back against
the wall so you know there's it's just
the whole thing's been a little bit of
you know not the prototypical request so
but right now we do the best we can with
what we're dealt with and get in the
ground early I don't think there's a
problem with that and getting the school
online as soon as we can the view that
this is such an extreme end of the town
and every time is a public safety
response it's aggravated by the distance
from everything so anything that
improves it up for you know I'm just
going on my own experience responded to
that neck of the woods you start to yell
so not to confuse things but sitting
over there
I heard someone there mentioned the
charter school school that we're talking
about on Avington Street is the so Shore
educational collaborative school I'm the
chairman of the board of that entity
this year so just for the clarity of the
public it's a social education and
collaborative the Charter School
actually is in an industrial park but
it's in Norwell thank you that's
probably my fault just man want to say
something join us at the microphone if
you would
sandra Duras at 36 Abington Street we're
kind of the other end of the tracks is
not that many of us up there there's 13
on the line on the water line it was
done in the 60s I know all about it all
the information about it every time we
turn around it's like oh they're just
there the end but we can put something
up I just heard about the storage
buildings which is not this meeting I
know but I wish there was some way that
the member of the residents of average
could notified I didn't know anything
about the storage I saw the the crane
company going up and I stopped in at the
planning board and I was told oh it's
just a they were just gonna put staging
and everything I don't know if any of
you have gone by that but that's
disgusting I don't I pity the people of
across the street it's just a mess it's
like a junkyard but that's just my
opinion anyway back to the Water Company
I did hear someone say maybe I got it
wrong the extension is the
responsibility of the people in Abington
Street or not is what you heard right
the us voting on so if you wanted to
extend it beyond beyond being proposed
to the N word Springwood lane or perhaps
sharp street that would be on the dime
of the applicant okay
I'm not for you can tell we had a
dead-end pipe which is not allowed
anymore I don't know too much about the
water company but I heard something
about a loop in your end I hope that
pipe it which is not a dead-end pipe
anymore it's up on by the collaborative
and they have to flush it is that what
you're going to put in gonna affect our
pipe that has to be flushed regularly it
happens to our water so this proposed
pipe and these pipes are
for the Quarian water system in the the
pipe you're connected to is the Abington
Rockland water system so they will not
be interconnected or connected and it
will still have the flush at the end
remember where I go to the end of what
you're gonna do these whoever operates
and maintains your system I believe they
will continue to do do it however they
do it I'm not aware of how they do it
but you don't know if the extension is
gonna so the extension that's in front
of the scene any Maps or anything I'm
sorry
so it starts from the school and goes to
the entrance of little sprouts and
that's where it ends there'll be a fire
hydrant right right there at the little
sprouts cool that's where the water main
will end and it'll be a connection going
into the little sprouts so that's the
limits and extents of the proposed water
main the blow-off to our 2 inch plastic
pipe is further down ok what I'm asking
is that going to be interfered at all
no okay that was some if we could if if
anything in the future is gonna go with
Abington Street the storage area I don't
know if our street is so terrible now
and just oh it seems like we're getting
but the residents have forgotten it
isn't that way yeah studied this and
we've been addressing it especially with
the issue of Union point
looming large on the horizon II now you
know I realized that there are buildings
on Sharpe street they're under
pressurized as well well I mean it all
figures into the mix ma'am yeah we're
we're trying as best we can you know
like my own view is that you know any
increased fire protection up there is a
plus thank you for all of the residents
there and you know if Hingham fire can
run a line from a new hydrant up to a
working fire that that's a good age not
if we have to pay for it so sorry well I
mean if you have to I heard last time a
meeting I forget was 14 2014 I think a
hundred eighty seven thousand we'd have
to pay for the
I think a little higher than that every
yeah in that I mean what I'm hearing
from the lieutenant is that a newly
installed fire hydrant would facilitate
the fire department's ability to run a
line to a working house fire on Abington
Street or Dennis Road or Hickey Road a
lot better than what's in place right
now is that right incorrect I'm sure I'm
sure I live across from the fire right
that was on Christmas Day it's just it's
financially when you talk about the 13
of us a lot of us are retired and lives
income and when you hit us with a price
of 200 but I don't wanna I want Abington
Rock on water I don't want a Clarion
water so we will not be charged if you
decide to run that extension to the end
of Abington Street on the Rockland end
correct that's another discussion for
another day ma'am no you know I we're
engaging in speculation the cost of
doing something like that are
considerable I don't know whether that
would be a discussion just involving the
residents or there would require a
greater one what the businesses on
Sharpe Street as well the extension that
you're doing now though for little
sprouts is not going to affect the cost
you would and man the other piece that I
would like to know is anytime anytime a
utility wants to do work in a street
whether it's gas or whether it's it's
the water company this this grant of
location process is a public process
that happens every time and and just as
you received a letter notifying you
about this meeting and some people did
that same process would happen so if
there was ever any consideration of
doing anything with the water main
further along Abington Street you would
be notified and have the opportunity to
come in this public forum to let people
know whether you like that idea or you
didn't like that idea am I correct so
you would be notified if there was any
future plan what's HAP
right now will will not affect will not
affect your water service you won't be
asked to pay for anything but as
selectmen Healy said you and your
neighbors will have the benefit of
having an additional fire hydrant and
some a large remain that will just help
with you know delivering water to that
area if God forbid it's needed against
if you already that's all certainly
mm-hmm
all of these hearings with respect to
these proposals for buildings that are
to be constructed anywhere in town are
subject to publication and that appears
of Hingham journal okay it's the
favorite part of my newspaper because
telling you track of what's going on
today I mean we got the okay and now for
the storage area that was in the hang of
journal all publish can I just ask I
will make sure I get the hang him
journal I don't read it from cover to
cover
sorry some things I don't want to read
cover to cover but can we just take care
of our 13 our 22 people in Abington
Street we're working on a bill I know
but it's bad the traffic is terrible
give us a sidewalk then but anyway I'll
make a motion to approve the request of
Aquarion to install and maintain
approximately 1350 feet of 8-inch
ductile iron water made in Abington
Street the new main will originate at
the driveway of number 75 research Road
approximately number 80 Abington Street
connecting into the existing eight inch
water main and continue under the paved
surface of Abington Street to completion
at approximately number 48
in order to service the daycare facility
little sprouts located at number 73
Abington Street also this project will
include one new hydrant this approval is
subject to the stipulation of the
Department of Public Works as outlined
in the letter dated February 11th 2019
second does it have to indicate that
it's going to be looped or that's know
second Steve me I just asked that if
there you point you mentioned that there
is the potential for something
conservation related may I please ask
that that that that you follow up with
Lani in in very short order because I
think as you've here to heard tonight
there are some folks that are sweating
the timing we can't control the weather
we hope the temperatures are cooperative
but let's let's do everything we can
right now to anticipate and be ready so
that so that people aren't any further
inconvenienced or stressed beyond what
what they've had to already agree I
reached out to law a couple weeks ago
when we knew we were submitting this
application just to give her heads-up we
were going to be here so post case will
contact it
Wow
well area was sheer is here is fabulous
to run it just to the foster show all
right
before we get to the next item we're
gonna jump ahead and just take agenda
item number look back this Andrea Andrew
you want some water
okay yes thank you
all right ladies and gentlemen I'm gonna
turn this over to Andrea a young
administrator for the hang of historical
fiction thank you
this is a proposal to set up the
preservation award evaluation committee
as we discussed at a meeting back in and
so we are the we agreed that we'd start
out with a oh thank you so much Shauna
house a seven-member committee and then
to go down to five members from then on
so what I put together here was is that
there will be several people who they've
agreed to serve for one year
Peter Bickford Suzanne Buchanan and then
Wilcox and so they will be part of the
seven-member committee in addition there
will be two other preservation award
design committee members this first year
and then we've got two new people Jack
Hobbs who's an architect and Jennifer
Schwartz who works for she's a member of
the Historical Society and she does all
sorts of great stuff so so the idea
being that the people who know the
rationale behind the award and the
criteria will be there at the beginning
and then just phase off so that what
we'll have left then
or people who understand the process and
and are knowledgeable about the criteria
so that's the way this hopefully this
makes sense
really thank you for staying with this
working so hard to put this together I
think it's a win-win for the town and I
think it's gonna be received very well
by the community it's implemented I
don't have any questions just at the
echo the thanks and to again we're so
lucky that people are willing to step
forward and volunteer to serve their
community well I like the way you've
done this work with sort of the original
group that as you suggest has the
institutional knowledge but then
involving new folks as this goes along
because that's part of it right is to
try to get the community and the public
involved in the in the appreciation of
our historic assets thank you I'll make
a motion to a point see the big fixes in
Buchanan had been talks to preservation
award evaluation committee for a
one-year term ending June 2019 second
all in favor aye
I'll entertain a motion to appoint Ben
Burnham in semi struggle house key to
the historic preservation award
evaluation committee for a two-year term
ending June 30th 2020 so moved second I
was a favor
entertain a motion to appoint Jack Hobbs
and Jennifer Schwarz to the historic
preservation award evaluation committee
for a two year term ending June 30th
so moved second all in favor aye thank
you thank you Andrew
thank you
don't forget you're reserving April the
7th that's when you're giving out these
awards April service all right item 10
on the agenda for tonight is the worn
article Z foster school article to amend
feasibility study vote School Committee
is present thank you I just wanted to
come tonight to give you some updated
information on warrant article Z on
behalf of the school committee we wanted
to inform you that we have decided to
withdraw the warrant article related to
foster school for this year and just to
note that while the article has been
withdrawn we did want to publicly
acknowledge here tonight that the Board
of Selectmen Advisory Committee and the
school committee all recognized that the
foster school is one of the top capital
priorities for the town and that time is
of the essence so for the next several
months the school committee is going to
be expending and diligently working on
the application to be accepted into the
MSBA eligibility period and we
respectfully would ask for you to
continue to support us in that and to
provide us for any assistance we may
need from time to time as we apply for
the SLI and what's the timing on that
Michelle bwaah the SOI is due April 11th
to the MSBA and that's being worked on
by the building committee the school
committee and mr. Ferris and of course
dr. gala and it's well on its way and we
have some good information to include in
that and so gets submitted in April and
then it gets considered over the summer
and ones yeah the diseases are in
December yeah so this year it was like
mid December that we heard okay yes
just wondering like um you know you and
I work or you and I were together for
the computer fair at foster a week or so
ago I'm just wondering about the
involvement of our state delegation in
some of this process because I know
senator Connor at least had offered to
try to facilitate some conversations ya
know is that something that would you
absolutely yeah I'm having the
legislators involved will be very
important and I think one thing that
would be helpful this year we're going
to invite the MSBA to come back for
another site visit he came in 2017 but
they did not come last year and things
have not gotten any better no and I do
think seeing the building I think it's a
complex layout and I think seeing the
challenges of delivering the program
within that kind of tricky space where
you have interior classrooms and you
know I think there's no substitute for
for seeing how that how that space is
currently being utilized right
absolutely I mean it's really not
conducive to 21st century learning I
mean they're doing great things they're
in the computer yes'm
and but I think you know I mean the
electrical system they're just support a
lot of the computer programming that
needs to be done so right okay so I
guess my if you need help from us I
suppose I'm facilitating any of that but
you know that may be one way we can be
helpful I know Ted went to the to the
meeting with the MSBA at foster in 2017
right iliza I'm obviously happy to do
any help we can do along the way talking
to legislators doing other things
okay I mean I do you know so Center
O'Connor
you know noted the reality that we've
we've all experienced which is you know
there are more schools putting in
applications that the buildings are
bigger and the pool of funds is just
what does it have sin on the sales tax
or something one cent
but once that on the sales tax so it's a
finite pool and you know instead of
being able to fund 20 projects like they
once were able to do they're able to
fund a
or something like that so I do feel like
the more we advocate for ourselves at
this point you know we've we've been
patient right we've we've experienced
their support in the past we've we've
also been patient on this project but as
you suggest the time of time is of the
essence for this but I guess I also I
also appreciate the focus on the MSBA
funding for this cycle
I appreciate that I know that probably
was not an easy decision for the school
committee to make and I do think it it
it shows the town that you're working
hard to get that done yes and that's
what we wanted to reflect and we thought
that was where our efforts her best
focus this year is trying to get this
funding from the MSBA and I know we we
voted the we made the necessary vote on
the SOI a couple of weeks ago but to the
extent over the next several months
there's you know I think we all want to
bring we all want to work together and
bring all of the resources of the town
to bear on really demonstrating this
need and so as as as this unfolds we'd
like to be helpful where we can I think
you know we in 2017 we as a town took
the sort of you know slightly unusual
step of asking Town Meeting to make the
feasibility funding available and to
form the building committees so that we
could be ready and I I understand I
understand that the conditions that the
conditions make it difficult I
understand that there are students
moving through the building and and if
you're as if you're a parent of a fourth
or a fifth grader a solution feels feels
pretty far off I you know I I totally
understand that and
at the same time I think there's a
shared realization that we have to do
something with foster school and and I I
hope we can all work together to just
demonstrate that need and make the most
compelling case we can to the state
absolutely thank you I have five sisters
and a brother go to foster five of my
children went there and two
grandchildren presently go there I
recognized the importance of the
neighborhood school I think when you
meet with the state you should take one
a little tour the shipyard and abused
rate I think you really need to impress
upon them that that is gonna be a
continuing demand yes school system no I
was talking today with our state
representative Jonas Kino pressing upon
her the need that we have for the
assistance all hands on deck to get the
kind of assistance we need to address
this effectively so thank you very much
for you decision you did thank you thank
you very much for coming tonight all
right
okay yes so we've been advised by by our
counsel that should the town vote to
acquire the water company that we
actually have a statutory requirement to
have a budget in place by certain
deadlines and that's what this is
intended to to accomplish can I just
make a couple comments about this budget
so I'll just be really brief so you know
there's there been a lot of questions
about about an Enterprise Fund and what
happens and things like that so in in
the next fiscal year if the town were to
purchase the water company we would keep
the rates that are currently set in
effect for that first year and that
means that we would be collecting a
little bit over 13 million dollars in
revenue and I just want to mention where
some of that money is going to be spent
because I think that there's been
there's a lot of information out there
so what would the budget covered the
budget would cover the salaries for the
water superintendent and an
administrative and some administrative
support and and that would be salaries
and benefits and that's about that's
about a quarter of a million dollars I'm
not going to read these numbers exactly
and there will be operating expenses of
about 4.4 million dollars which is the
cost for the daily operations and
maintenance which the town is proposing
be outsourced initially then there's
about eight hundred and thirty thousand
dollars which is a payment in lieu of
taxes and the important thing here is
that right now the aquarian Water
Company or I guess eversource if you
will
pays the town property taxes for all the
land it owns and and in the financial
model that the town's put together it
proposes that
the Undertown ownership the water
company would continue to make that
payment but it would be a payment in
lieu of taxes which is very similar to
what what hangin like does and so what
that means is that we're not taking
we're not taking parcels off the
property tax roll we're not gonna lose
revenue as a town we're just going to be
acquired getting it in a different way
and then the debt service for both the
acquisition and the capital investment
in that first year would be about 2.7
million dollars so essentially what's
going to happen in year 1 is that the is
that the expenses are going to be about
eight eight point two million dollars
but we're collecting thirteen million
dollars in revenue so what we are
proposing and we've talked with Jean
Montgomery on this which has been really
helpful is that is that we we will have
a surplus in that first year of just
under five million dollars and what we
would propose is that that that'd be a
line item in the budget so that if there
are any unusual or extraordinary
expenses that come to bear we have funds
available so essentially what what
what's going to happen is that in this
first year we will build up close to a
five million dollar rainy day fund in
the first year alone and there's been a
lot of questions from people about you
know what what happens if there's an
unexpected expense or suggestions that
the town of Hingham would need to that
Hingham taxpayers we would use Hingham
taxpayer money if if there was a budget
issue at the water company what we've
contemplated in this year one budget is
that we will we will begin to accumulate
a surplus and by the way that surplus
will remain in the water company down
the road if we want to we can establish
a rate Stabilization Fund we could
establish a capital Stabilization Fund
but this gives us the maximum
flexibility and you know I think it's
it's pretty remarkable that in the first
year of a budget for an operation like
this
you know having a having a budget
surplus of close to five million dollars
on a thirteen million dollar revenue
base just just really puts us in a very
healthy in a strong position and I think
with respect to the questions about
something unexpected that comes up
I feel like this puts us in a really
good position so I'd also note that in
in subsequent years in year two year
three that that budget surplus will be a
little smaller because at that time we'd
go into we'd be issuing long-term debt
but I I i think it's it's both
noteworthy and it provides a level of
protection and assurance for both
ratepayers and for Hingham taxpayers
thank you we'll continue to speak on
this issue and as the day's rollout will
provide more details for them they
intend to do there as well we're
continuing to have these issues as well
as other matters associated with the
acquisition of the Water Company
discussed by a different town boards so
I'd like to thank the residents for the
continued attention to this
generationally important issue I make a
motion on the budget sure I'd make a
motion that whoops oh here's the vote
list sorry about that I just want to
make sure these the right language I'd
make a motion to approve the water
company Enterprise Fund budget for
fiscal year 22nd I
Epstein emotional open the war the 2019
annual town meeting will move article KK
Mary building committee an article ll
library building project can't close to
warrant so moved second all those in
favor
I make a motion to approve the request
have discovered him for the taste of
Hingham to be held on Saturday May 18
2000 19th and 12:00 p.m. to 3:00 p.m.
with the rain date of Sunday may not
22,000 19 to 12 p.m. to 3 p.m. this
event will be held on Main Street
between elm and North Street as well as
on the sidewalk so moved second all in
favor all right
tonight alert thank you no thank you I'm
good I think it's a Smart TVs something
like that I just like the public to know
the fact that they're still smiling as a
testament had a couple shout outs via
gum Hingham high school girls winter
track team state champions way to go
ladies
yard me say to the school committee
folks I stopped by at the foster school
commuter probe computer programming fair
its supported in large part by the
Hingham Education Foundation and it was
just you know it was a blast it was a
Friday morning and these kids can do
more on their laptops the
I can't even imagine so there they are
starting basic coding in kindergarten
all the way up and it was just really
really fun to watch the kids work it in
collaborative groups and you know it was
good good again to also get over to
foster school and then last but not
least we got a we got a press release
right Sally from the the air force that
there's a Hingham native who is a staff
sergeant in the Air Force special
tactics group a guy named Daniel
Kelleher and he is joining with 18 of
his comrades to Rock 830 miles across
five states in honor of 20 Airmen killed
in action who were part were part of the
Air Force special tactics team and if
you don't know what a ruck is I did look
it up to be sure but I I ran in a road
race once and I thought I was speeding
along and all of a sudden these guys in
full gear with backpacks and and boots
came flying by me that's what these guys
are doing they're they're just in their
fatigues with their backpacks and
they're gonna cover eight hundred and
thirty miles in support of their
comrades so - - daniel Kelleher we
salute you sir I would just note that
Lincoln Day is Lincoln Day is always a
great day I hope I'm not my taking your
thunder I'm good I'm gonna save the rest
of for you and just say I was glad to be
there and enjoyed the day you know I
Lincoln day is just so much fun no
matter where you're sitting in the
church it's a historic gathering you can
sing patriotic songs and you can just
envision that the great history that
this town has had
you know I I can't recommend it enough
and it is truly a favorite I want to
expand a little bit on what Karen said
about this particular ruck march I've
seen a couple of pictures of my son
after he got through a rock it's it's a
grueling exercise and this the b-fos has
a special tactics unit which flies into
war zones under fire and rescues wounded
soldiers and takes them out and these
helicopters and along and then this is
in the mountains of Afghanistan and
they're doing this eight hundred and
thirty-five mile five-state march in
honor of the men and women who have been
killed doing this kind of incredibly
brave work there's been a Medal of Honor
awarded to one of them there's been ten
Air Force crosses in 44 Silver Stars so
it just speaks to the bravery and it's
it's privilege and an honor that we have
such a an individual in that unit that
comes from this town side
Staff Sergeant Daniel Kelleher so if you
see the family of Staff Sergeant make
sure you extend your compliments with
that I'll take a motion to adjourn
I looked second all right